Guide to the Rice University Provost Office Records: James Kinsey (interim) and David Auston, 1993-1995 UA 098
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Provost Office Records: James Kinsey (interim) and David Auston
1993-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Auston, David
UA 098
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
These records reflect the daily business of the Provost's office under interim Provost James Kinsey and Provost David Auston (1993-). They reveal the daily business of the Provost's Office, which has the overall responsibility for the institution's educational and research programs.
Biographical Note
James Kinsey, Dean of Rice University's Wiess School of Natural Sciences, was named interim provost by university president Malcolm Gillis in July 1993. The provost position was vacated by Neal Lane when he left Rice to become director of the National Science Foundation.
Kinsey came to Rice in 1988 as dean of Wiess School after 25 years at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology as a chemistry professor. He also served as Chairman of MIT's chemistry department for five years during his tenure.
Excerpted from Rice University News Release, July 23, 1993.
David Auston was named provost by university president Malcolm Gillis in August 1994. He was Columbia's dean of engineering and applied science and the Morris and Alma Schapiro Professor of Engineering. He was member of both the National Academy of Sciences and the National Academy of Engineering. He earned his undergraduate and master's degree from the University of Toronto and his Ph.D. from the University of California at Berkeley.
Excerpted from Rice University News Release, May 19, 1994.
Scope and Contents
These records reflect the daily business of the Provost's office under interim Provost James Kinsey and Provost David Auston (1993-). They reveal the daily business of the Provost's Office, which has the overall responsibility for the institution's educational and research programs. These files were previously intermingled with the files of the preceeding provost, Neal Lane. The files contain correspondence with the academic and non-academic departments.
Access Restrictions
Permission to access these records must be obtained from the Provost's Office. Contact the Woodson Research Center for instructions.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Accruals
Additional materials related to Kinsey / Auston tenure are expected to be transfered to the Woodson Research Center in the future.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Provost's Office.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Education
Document Types
letters (correspondence); reports; memorandums
Subjects (Persons)
Auston, David; Kinsey, James
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Office of the Provost
- Series I: On Campus - General, 99323
  - Academic Deans, 1993; 146054 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Deans, Faculty Positions Allocations, August-September 1993; 146055 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Deans, Faculty Positions Allocations, September 1993; 146056 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Continuing Studies, 1994, 99331 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Distribution Courses, 1994-95, 99330 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foundation Courses, 1994, 99329 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - (Office of) Graduate Programs, 1993-94, 99328 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rice Institute for Policy Analysis (RIPA), 1994, 99327 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rice Quantum Institute (RQI), 1994, 99326 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Rice University Press, 1993, 99325 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rice University School Mathematics Project (RUSMP), 1994, 99324 (Box 1, Folder 11)